Hemal Khatri

Leeds, United Kingdom,

+44-7771028488, hemal@ocean-across.com

PROFILE

Seasoned business leader with a 13-year entrepreneurial journey, building a venture from the ground up and scaling the team from 10 to 100. Adept at forging rapid connections, driving new business growth, and securing sales closures. Committed to exceptional customer service, nurturing enduring client relationships, and skill-fully managing requests and challenges. Known for an optimistic, proactive, and goal-focused approach. Successfully expanded operations into diverse sectors, fuelling overall business diversification and success.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jan 2006 — Dec 2009

Centre Manager, Axiom BPM Services PVT Ltd

USA/Ahmedabad

- I embarked on my journey in the professional realm as an agent, diligently honing my skills and
 gradually ascending the ranks to ultimately assume the role of a center manager within a span of just
 three years. However, driven by an entrepreneurial spirit and a desire for new horizons, I decided to
 tender my resignation and embarkon the path of creating and nurturing my own business venture.
- Call Centre Services
- Tele Sales Services
- Outbound Sales Services
- Inbound Customer Care
- Lead Generation
- Operations

Feb 2010 — Nov 2018

Co-Founder & Director, Ocean Across BPM Services PVT Ltd

USA/Ahmedabad

- I co-founded Ocean Across with a close friend and a lean team of 10 employees. Our initial clients (U.S Base), whochampioned new entrepreneurs, supported us as we diligently delivered their needs.

 Through disciplined efforts, we fuelled their growth, leading to increased business. Over time, our client base expanded, and eventually our ocean-across family had 100 members and 2 homes.
- Business Development
- Client Co-ordination
- Call Centre Services
- Outbound Sales Services
- Inbound Customer Care
- Lead Generation

Jan 2019 — Aug 2020

Recruitment Team Manager, Ocean Across Staffing Inc.

USA

- Responsibilities include recruiting U.S candidates of particular skills for our clients.
- Worked with a variety of requirements from IT, Healthcare and Telecom and Engineering domain.
- Expertise in using sourcing tools like LinkedIn, Google, CareerBuilder, and Monster etc.
- Sourced and Screened candidates resumes to the client requirements, to determine the best applicant for the iob.
- Negotiated wage rates and benefit packages and other terms and conditions of employment with candidates.
- Gained commitment from candidates for current and future job requirements.
- Underwent full recruitment life cycle with the candidates.
- Maintained a professional and consistent relationship with the clients/customers.
- Prepared candidates for all job interviews by providing detailed information on the company, the hiring
- manager, our business strategy, department background, job descriptions, and expectations walked in candidates for interviews and start dates to the client site.

Sep 2020 — Nov 2022

Recruitment Team Manager, Ocean Across Staffing Inc.

UK

- Working for UK's leading facilities Management Company.
- Blue collar hiring: Cleaners, Labourers and Administrator / Receptionist.
- Requirements are for temporary including full time and part time (1 day to 6 months)
- Extensive knowledge of the company's process & Operations.
- Good experience managing VMS and other job portals.
- Prioritizing requirements and sharing in team.
- Help the recruiting team by providing them creative sourcing suggestion on positions.
- Responsible for team member's performance, deliveries and achieving targets.
- Weekly one-to-one catch up with team to support on their projects, challenges, management initiatives, and personal development.
- Resolving internal conflicts and boosting up the team's morale.

- Working with the Account Manager / Client to obtain feedback on the submittals and pushing the strong candidates to the client.
- Developing and implementing plans and strategies.
- Analyzing and making different reports like KPI reports, DPR (Daily progress report) and GP report.
- Attending client calls as needed.

Dec 2022 — Apr 2023

Recruitment Team Manager, Ocean Across Staffing Inc. (Client Employher)

USA

- Responsibilities include recruiting U.S candidates of particular skills for our clients.
- Worked with a variety of requirements from IT, Healthcare and Telecom and Engineering domain.
- Expertise in using sourcing tools like LinkedIn, Google, CareerBuilder, and Monster etc.
- Sourced and Screened candidates resumes to the client requirements, to determine the best applicant for the job.
- Negotiated wage rates and benefit packages and other terms and conditions of employment with candidates.
- Gained commitment from candidates for current and future job requirements.
- Underwent full recruitment life cycle with the candidates.
- Maintained a professional and consistent relationship with the clients/customers.
- Prepared candidates for all job interviews by providing detailed information on the company, the hiring
- manager, our business strategy, department background, job descriptions, and expectations walked in candidates for interviews and start dates to the client site.

EDUCATION				
Apr 2004 — Mar 2005	H.S.C, Gujarat Law Society			Ahmedabad
Apr 2005 — Mar 2008	Bachelors of Commerce, Gujarat University			Ahmedabad
Mar 2021 — Aug 2021	Technical Analyst, Virtual Learning			ONLINE
SKILLS	Leadership	Experienced	Emotion Intelligence	Experienced
	Communication	Experienced	Negotiation	Experienced
	Team Work	Experienced	Critical Thinking	Experienced
	Customer Service	Experienced		
LANGUAGES	English	Highly proficient	Gujarati	Native speaker
	Hindi	Highly proficient	Sanskrit	Working knowledge

HOBBIES

Passionate about traveling, trekking, and embracing new challenges in the great outdoors. Certified P3 Pilot(paragliding), combining love for flying and exploration. I learned swimming very late but I am glad I can say it is my hobby now. Avid reader of self-awareness and spiritual growth literature, continuously seeking personal development and enhanced understanding.

Former professional cricket player with 7 years of experience representing school, district, and state teams. Demonstrates discipline, teamwork, and dedication.

These interests underscore my diverse skills, dedication, and adaptability, contributing to a well-rounded and dynamic persona.